<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-07-21T19:37:47+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Your awesome title</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mybp" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2020-07-21T16:39:56+08:00</published><updated>2020-07-21T16:39:56+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mybp">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll requires blog post files to be named according to the following format:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR-MONTH-DAY-title.MARKUP&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YEAR&lt;/code&gt; is a four-digit number, &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MONTH&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;DAY&lt;/code&gt; are both two-digit numbers, and &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;MARKUP&lt;/code&gt; is the file extension representing the format used in the file. After that, include the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="jekyll" /><category term="update" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">First Blog Post: Baby Steps of a Rising Programmer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/baby-steps/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="First Blog Post: Baby Steps of a Rising Programmer" /><published>2020-07-17T16:39:00+08:00</published><updated>2020-07-17T16:39:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/thoughts/baby-steps</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/thoughts/baby-steps/">&lt;p&gt;First Blog Post: A Programmer’s Baby Steps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year ago, I quit my job at a factory in 	Dongguan, China and went home. Due to geographical restrictions, long working hour (often from 8a.m. to 8p.m.), and six-day workweek, I had minimal time spared to do any non-work activities, not to mention meeting anyone out of work. What I want the ost is to meet new people and make connections, but the job simply did not provide enough opportunities. So, I handed in that letter and waved goodbye to the company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My plan was to take a short break and start a new career. However, things went wrong as the pandemic began breaking out of control.  I almost got a job at a bank in January  2020. Unfortunately, the bank froze all headcount as the news of the coronavirus spreads.  Imagine you are in a football match, you dribbled pass the last player of the opponent team. All of a sudden, a racoon came out of nowhere and stole the ball away before you claim your goal. (What’s worse, the racoon is still here pestering all of us!) Since then, the job market became quiet. And I started looking around for other options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Programming was one of the things that I looked into. To be honest, I did not expect to enjoy it at all. I learned a little bit of coding with VBA at school. I only used it once to build a small petty cash bookkeeping application. Coding with VBA did not add too much value to my previous jobs, and I definitely won’t re-learn it unless somebody pays me enough money. But Python took me to a whole new world. I started learning it by taking an introductory course taught by Dr Charles Severance: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.coursera.org/specializations/python&quot;&gt;Python for Everybody&lt;/a&gt;. The course was really eye-opening. I did not know that I could parse a website or generate graphs for data representation with just a few lines of codes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I am taking more programming courses on different platforms with various instructors, soaking my brain in codes everyday. I hope I can learn more and utilize what I learned to eventually build something awe-inspiring. This little blog post is a small step, I will follow up with more and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;p.s. This website is under construction. I will make it look prettier, but the posts can go first.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>mics13</name></author><category term="thoughts" /><summary type="html">First Blog Post: A Programmer’s Baby Steps</summary></entry></feed>